# **Stephen Godfrey**

Palo Alto, CA / 650-475-6159 / stephengodfrey.net / stephengodfrey223@gmail.com

## SUMMARY

Analytical thinker and strategic planner with a proven track record of driving new initiatives to successful completions and through a unique combination of managerial experience, quantitative skills and passion, helping firms design strategies, build products and deliver results

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Product definition and road mapping
- Initiative management
- Quantitative analysis
- Statistical regression and classification modeling
- Machine learning techniques
- Natural language processing
- Data visualization
- Python, SQL, Visual Basic

### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly Data Science Immersive May 2019

University of California, Los Angeles – The Anderson School MBA, 1993

# University of California, Los Angeles

BS Applied Mathematics/ Economics, 1989

## **VOLUNTEER**

Member UCLA Math and Stats Chair's Council

Member Board of Trustees of First Congregational Church of Palo Alto

## CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

**eCommerce leadership** led Foreign Exchange (FX) eCommerce teams for two major banks providing client-facing user-interface and API tools and each generating over \$350MM in annual revenue

**New product delivery** responsible for the successful launch of new products including an API suite, an online portal and online trading applications

**Quantitative analysis** demonstrated expertise in applying quantitative techniques including building a financial risk research service, authoring papers and pursuing a data science immersive program

**Broad management** led product management, sales, service, trading and research teams of over 50 members

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Wells Fargo Bank Head of FX eCommerce, San Francisco • 2010 to 2018 • Led product management, domain sales and service for the \$350MM-revenue electronic FX revenue division • Delivered user interface and API products to clients • Prioritized, funded and executed the eFX product roadmap • Spearheaded major infrastructure and compliance buildouts

**Bank of America Merrill Lynch** Co-head of FX eSolutions, San Francisco, London, Los Angeles • 1992 to 2010

 Co-led the global electronic trading, cross-currency payment and consumer FX teams generating \$400MM in annual revenue • Sold hedging solutions to multinational corporations • Spearheaded launch of the GCIB portal • Co-created a risk-assessment research group to work with clients and publish research

Sanwa Trust Bank Equity Analyst, Los Angeles • 1992

Built quantitative models for equity valuation and portfolio selection

TSA Capital Management Quant Analyst, Los Angeles • 1989 to 1992

Built statistical asset allocation models